Contact

Metro Manila, Philippines 0927342489 (Mobile) johncanero.official@gmail.c om

www.linkedin.com/in/johncanero (LinkedIn) johncanero-website.vercel.app/ (Portfolio) bio.link/johncanero (Portfolio) github.com/johncanero (Portfolio)

Top Skills

React.js
Cascading Style Sheets (CSS)
JavaScript

Languages

English (Native or Bilingual) Filipino (Native or Bilingual)

Certifications

Start the UX Design Process: Empathize, Define, and Ideate Introduction to Programming and Computer Science - Full Course

The Complete Web Development Bootcamp

Learn React for Free: The Ultimate React 101

Foundations of User Experience (UX) Design

John Cañero

React Developer, Front-End Engineer, Architecture Student - Aspiring people to build and create stuffs | React • Next Js • JavaScript • Typescript • CSS • Tailwind CSS

Quezon City, National Capital Region, Philippines

Summary

I enjoy creating stuffs. I like to BUILD. To have fun, help people and show my work to the world. This is where I come in.

MY STORY:

Early back in my childhood and early teens, I usually love to draw architectural houses on a paper. The passion behind building and sketching houses helped me paved the way on choosing the program I like in College: Architecture.

Right now, I am currently studying in University of Santo Tomas taking up BS Architecture. I am grateful and happy in my growth and journey in the institution. My design philosophy throughout my student experience in every project I create: "The role of architecture is to design spaces for people and making them happy."

This philosophy helped me a lot when designing and building stuffs that focuses on users.

TECH JOURNEY:

At the other side of the field, I spend my time learning on technology especially the Frontend Development and UX (User Experience) and it helped me experience and see the opportunities at the tech sector. I consistently learn the concepts and tools behind and building projects around it.

In the future, my career aspiration would be to develop and build products that would uplift humankind. With the experiences I had, it helped me to empathize the users and realize what are their needs and wants. To always focus and center the user and make them happy.

HIGHLIGHTS:

Graduated at The Complete Web Development Bootcamp 2022 # Accomplished Google - Foundations of User Experience (UX) Design Certificate

Accomplished Google - Start the UX Design Process: Empathize, Define, and Ideate Certificate

Software Engineer/Developer at Upskill Education

Project Manager and EA to Community Development (2018-2020) at Heritage Conservation Society- UST Chapter

Learn React for Free: The Ultimate React 101 at Scrimba

(Architecture) - : Architectural Design, AutoCAD, SketchUp, Revit, Enscape, Lumion, Vray, Adobe Lightroom and Adobe Photoshop.

(Web Development) - : JavaScript, TypeScript, React Js, Next Js, HTML, HTML5, CSS3, Tailwind CSS, Bootstrap, Netlify, Vercel, Node Js, Express Js, MongoDB, NPM, Git, GitHub, Front-End Development, Web Development, Figma, Canva and UI/UX Design.

:

When I have free time and no work, I enjoy # playing football, table tennis, badminton, ♂# cycling, ♂# running, ★# playing board games such as chess, and reading growth and development books.

: https://johncanero-digitalcard.vercel.app/

Experience

Upskill Education
Software Engineer/Developer
March 2022 - Present (10 months)
Metro Manila, National Capital Region, Philippines

I am actively learning the technology in the web development field as a parttime study hobby. I would like utilize my strengths in the love of learning, creativity, problem-solving and the importance of delivering quality and essential products to users. : JavaScript, TypeScript, React Js, Next Js, HTML, HTML5, CSS3, Tailwind CSS, Bootstrap, Netlify, Vercel, Node Js, Express Js, MongoDB, NPM, Git, GitHub, Front-End Development, Web Development, Figma, Canva and UI/UX Design.

Udemy

Graduated at The Complete Web Development Bootcamp March 2022 - August 2022 (6 months)

National Capital Region, Philippines

Heritage Conservation Society 2 years

Project Manager 2019 - 2020 (1 year)

National Capital Region, Philippines

I am part of the organization in the (University of Santo Tomas - Chapter) promoting the richness and culture of heritage in the country. The role is essential in terms of inviting and contacting the speakers, managing the documents and giving the importance of our heritage of our nation. With the help of my associates and peers of the organization, we managed several papers that is needed and required to submit for the preparation of the events of the organization.

One of the projects I co-handled: Baybayin Buhayin: A Alphabetic Writing System Workshop that promotes the beauty and writing of the Philippine Script Heritage.

Executive Associate to Community Development 2018 - 2019 (1 year)

National Capital Region, Philippines

The role is significant in managing the papers for the preparation of events and documentation in the community development programs. I am part of the organization in the (University of Santo Tomas - Chapter).

Education

University of Santo Tomas
Senior High School, (STEM) Science, Technology, Engineering, and
Mathematics · (2016 - 2018)

San Beda University

Junior High School · (2013 - 2016)

University of Santo Tomas

Bachelor of Science in Architecture, Architecture · (2018)